Hey everyone, and thanks for jumping
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about
Bitcoin. It's almost crunch time. If you
guys like the content, make sure you
subscribe to the channel, give the video
a thumbs up, and also check out the sale
on IntoTheCryptoverse Premium at
intothecryptoverse.com.
As I mentioned a few months ago, we we
do have the direct access option as well
for those wanting something a little bit
more in-depth.
Um Bitcoin is trading at around $64,000,
64 or 65,000. And listen, guys, I've
done this a number of times before
through these midterm years, and
historically, it's always played out the
same way.
Bitcoin sells off
at the very end of the post-halving
year.
No one believes it's the bear market.
Some people start to believe by
February. More people begin to believe
by the summer.
But when I say it's almost crunch time,
what I mean is this. A lot of times,
Bitcoin will form a low
in the summer, but it's not always it's
not necessarily like the low, it's just
a low. So, looking at the summer of
2022, the summer of 2026, you also have
the summer of 2018. Okay?
And then, what happens after that is
that there's just not a lot of
volatility. Like Bitcoin doesn't really
do anything. And yes, there's people
talking about could Bitcoin go back up
to 70k, but a lot of that stuff is
irrelevant right now, right? The point
is is that there's just not a lot of
interest in crypto. And it might feel
different than in prior times, but
there's a little secret here.
And when you look at the social
interest, I think a lot of people are
thinking about what it was like back in
2022. But if you look at Bitcoin
in 2026, and look at where the social
interest is, we're at 0.2.
4 years ago, exactly 4 years ago, at the
same time in the cycle, social interest
was at 0.5 almost, 0.4 to 0.5. So, there
was more than double the amount of
interest in crypto
4 years ago, pre-FTX,
than there is now. But, in 2018,
in August of 2018, the social risk was
also 0.2. So, we've been here before.
Social interest is declining. To a lot
of people, it feels like the cryptoverse
is dying.
But, what I'm saying is that it's almost
crunch time. And what happens is you
form a low in the summer, volatility
basically completely dries up. Look at
2018.
Look at 2022.
And then what happens is some event at
the end of the year
causes this final drop.
I can't promise that, right? But, that's
what normally happens.
And
it wakes everyone back up.
One of the problems I think right now is
like, you know, 60K for you know, it
seems like a reasonable price, right? I
mean, given the fact that Bitcoin's
traded a lot of above it for a lot of
the last several years. But, at the same
time,
there's a lot of indicators that would
suggest, "Hey, you know, you could go
lower." Especially if you look at like
the on-chain indicators, things like the
NVRVZ score, for example.
Uh that's a really interesting indicator
that shows you that Bitcoin normally
bottoms out when the NVRVZ score goes
below zero. Hasn't done that yet.
There's a few other metrics like that
that you could argue tell the same
thing. So, it's like there's people that
are buying Bitcoin, right? I picked some
up. But, the point is is like there's
still a number of indicators that
haven't really
given the the all-clear, if you will.
Not that they have to. I mean, it's
always possible the market just leaves
those indicators behind.
But, the way it normally plays out a low
in the summer, volatility dries up in
the July, August, September, and then
something happens.
And it wakes everyone back up.
And it brings people back, and then the
next bull market starts. We are pre that
event, in my opinion. We are before that
event. I don't think that that event,
whatever that event is, I don't think
it's happened yet.
But, I think it's going to happen
relatively soon.
It's almost crunch time. Look, and we've
talked about this for months, how that
Bitcoin would spend time basically
between the 200-week moving average and
the bear market resistance band.
And what's going to happen is as the
year goes on, it's going to force the
decision at some point soon. It's going
to force this to to decide what is it
actually going to do. Is it going to
break up? Is it going to break down?
I would I mean, again, I don't know for
sure. I would lean towards breakdown
because that's what it normally does
near the end of midterm years.
But, only time will tell. It's almost
crunch time. It's coming up soon. What I
think, though, by late November,
I think the low will either be in
or very, very close to being in.
Which is why
the ITC conference is in late November.
I think the low could be in October,
could even be late September. Some
circumstances, it could be December.
October is the most likely month, in my
opinion, but that doesn't mean it has to
be then.
The conference, November 20th through
the 22nd, with the main day on November
21st. So, we're doing it late November,
so that we can bring everyone together
after theoretically, whatever this event
is, happens.
And hopefully, we can bring together
some, you know, some more rational minds
to talk about what's going on in the
market. Would love to have you guys
there. Tickets are going to go up on
September 1st. So, if you've been
planning on going, but you haven't
gotten your ticket yet, I would to you
to do so because the ticket prices will
be going up in in just about um 3 weeks
or so. So, make sure you guys go ahead
and get your ticket um and uh I would
recommend doing that relatively soon.
And then as I've mentioned before as
well, uh we've got a lot of great
speakers. We're going to continue adding
speakers. Um
and if you're not, you know, if you're
if you're not sure
um about any of the logistics, we have
some of the details here on the website
like where you could stay and whatnot as
well. So, make sure you guys check that
out. Link in the description below.
It's almost crunch time. We got the low
in the summer. We got the low in
February, right? We said low in
February, bounce, low in late June,
early July.
Bounce again.
At some point, Bitcoin might be
overstaying its welcome.
Because remember,
you get the bounce from the low in the
summer,
but in 2018, that bounce only lasted
into late July.
In 2022, it lasted into mid-August. So,
I don't think Bitcoin has overstayed its
welcome just yet
at these levels.
But crunch time normally shows up
late August, September, October. Right?
And in some cases, it goes all the way
into November, December. Even in in
2015, it was January. And I mean, to
speculate dubiously, you have a low
2015, it was January. The next one was
December. The next one was November.
Extrapolation is dangerous, but if you
were to extrapolate, October seems like
a
um
a candidate month. So, again, I know
I've been saying October all year long.
I don't know if it's going to be
October. I think that's the most likely
month. And now that it's only 2 months
away,
crunch time is almost here. So,
don't become complacent. Be aware of
what's happening in the market. And and
we'll see how this shapes up over the
next couple of months and and hopefully
it does so in a in a manner that is
still resembling other cycles and then
hopefully we can kick that next bull
market off. Again, if you guys like the
content, make sure you subscribe, give
the video a thumbs up, check out the
conference. Again, September 1st is when
prices are going up.
And also check out Into The Cryptoverse
Premium. I'll see you guys next time.
Bye.